<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<resources>

    <string name="app_name">Capture the City</string>
    <string name="share">share</string>
    <string name="capture">capture</string>
    <string name="congratulations">Congratulations!!</string>
    <string name="captured_msg">You have captured </string>
    <string name="tab_monuments">Monuments</string>
    <string name="tab_monument">Monument</string>
    <string name="tab_map">Map</string>
    <string name="ok">Ok</string>

    <string name="see_more">Capture the monument to see more</string>

    <string name="title_fuente_cibeles">Fuente de Cibeles</string>
    <string name="title_puerta_alcala">Puerta de Alcalá</string>
    <string name="title_calle_alcala">Calle de Alcalá</string>
    <string name="title_cat_almudena">C. de la Almudena</string>
    <string name="title_templo_debod">Templo de Debod</string>
    <string name="title_palacio_real">Palacio Real</string>
    <string name="title_plaza_mayor">Plaza mayor</string>
    <string name="title_retiro">Parque del Retiro</string>
    <string name="title_sol">Puerta del Sol</string>
    <string name="title_palacion_com">P. de Comunicaciones</string>
    <string name="title_teatro">Teatro Real</string>
    <string name="title_teleferico">Teleférico</string>

    <string name="calle_alacala" formatted="false" >Calle de Alcalá is the longest street in Madrid. It starts at the
        Puerta del Sol and goes on for 10.5 km, to the northeastern outskirts of the city. Henry
        David Inglis described it in 1837 as \"long, of superb width, and flanked by a splendid
        range of unequal buildings\".

        \n\nCalle de Alcalá is one of the oldest streets in the city. It was the old road which led
        to the city of Alcalá de Henares (from which it takes the name) and continued to Aragón;
        today, this route is covered by the A-2 motorway. Along this street
        it is possible to find landmarks such as Banco Bilbao Vizcaya at number 16, the former
        Alcalá 20 discothèque at number 20, Edificio Metrópolis, the Unión y el Fénix Español
        building at number 23, Círculo de Bellas Artes, Plaza de Cibeles, Puerta de Alcalá,
        the Spanish Ministry of Education, the Instituto Cervantes HQ building,
        the Bank of Spain building, Parque del Buen Retiro and Plaza de Toros de Las Ventas.</string>

    <string name="catedral_almudena" formatted="false">  Santa María la Real de La Almudena is the
        Catholic cathedral in Madrid, the seat of the Roman Catholic Archdiocese of Madrid. It was
        consecrated by Pope John Paul II in 1993.

        \n\nWhen the capital of Spain was transferred from Toledo to Madrid in 1561, the seat of the
        Church in Spain remained in Toledo and the new capital had no cathedral. Plans to build a
        cathedral in Madrid dedicated to the Virgin of Almudena were discussed as early as the 16th
        century but even though Spain built more than 40 cities in the new world during that century
        and plenty of Cathedrals, the cost of expanding and keeping the Empire came first and the
        construction of Madrid\'s cathedral was postponed. Making the cathedral the largest that the
        world had ever seen was then a priority, all other main Spanish cities had centuries old
        Cathedrals, Madrid also has old churches but the construction of Almudena only began in 1879.

        \n\nThe cathedral seems to have been built on the site of a medieval mosque that was destroyed
        in 1083 when Alfonso VI reconquered Madrid. Francisco de Cubas, the Marquis of Cubas, designed
        and directed the construction in a Gothic revival style. Construction ceased completely during
        the Spanish Civil War, and the project was abandoned until 1950, when Fernando Chueca Goitia
        adapted the plans of de Cubas to a baroque exterior to match the grey and white façade of
        the Palacio Real, which stands directly opposite. The cathedral was not completed until 1993,
        when it was consecrated by Pope John Paul II. On May 22, 2004, the marriage of King Felipe VI,
        then crown prince, to Letizia Ortiz Rocasolano took place at the cathedral.

        \n\nThe Neo-Gothic interior is uniquely modern, with chapels and statues of contemporary artists,
        in heretogeneous styles, from historical revivals to "pop-art" decor. The Blessed Sacrament
        Chapel features mosaic from known artist Fr. Marko Ivan Rupnik.
        </string>

    <string name="fuente_cibeles">The fountain of Cibeles is a neo-classical complex of
        marble sculptures with fountains that has become an iconic symbol for the city of Madrid.
        It sits at the intersection of Calle de Alcalá (running from east to west), Paseo de Recoletos
        (to the North) and Paseo del Prado (to the south). Plaza de Cibeles was originally named
        Plaza de Madrid, but in 1900, the City Council named it Plaza de Castelar, which was
        eventually replaced by its current name.

        \n\nIt is currently delimited by four prominent buildings: The Bank of Spain, the Palacio de
        Buenavista, the Palacio de Linares and the Cybele Palace. These constructions are located in
        four different neighbourhoods from three different adjacent districts: Centro, Retiro and
        Salamanca.

        \n\nIn the years Cybele Palace and her fountain have become symbolic monuments of the city.</string>

    <string name="puerta_alcala">The Puerta de Alcalá ("Alcalá Gate") is a Neo-classical monument in
        the Plaza de la Independencia in Madrid, Spain. It stands near the city center and several
        meters away from the main entrance to the Parque del Buen Retiro. The square is bisected by
        Alcalá Street, although the street does not cross through the monument, and it is the origin
        of the Alfonso XII, Serrano and Olózaga streets. Its name originates from the old path from
        Madrid to the nearby town of Alcalá de Henares.

        \n\nMadrid in the late 18th century, still remained a somewhat drab villa in appearance,
        surrounded by medieval walls. Around the year 1774, king Charles III commissioned Francesco
        Sabatini to construct a monumental gate in the city wall through which an expanded road to
        the city of Alcalá was to pass, replacing an older, smaller, gate which stood nearby.
        It was inaugurated in 1778.</string>
    <string name="templo_debod">
        The Temple of Debod (Spanish: Templo de Debod) is an ancient Egyptian temple which was
        dismantled and rebuilt in Madrid, Spain.

        \n\nThe temple was built originally 15 kilometres (9.3 mi) south of Aswan in southern Egypt very
        close to the first cataract of the Nile and to the great religious center dedicated to the
        goddess Isis, in Philae. In the early 2nd century BC, Adikhalamani (Tabriqo), the Kushite king
        of Meroë, started its construction by building a small single room chapel dedicated to the
        god Amun. It was built and decorated on a similar design to the later Meroitic chapel on which
        the Temple of Dakka is based. Later, during the reigns of Ptolemy VI, Ptolemy VIII and
        Ptolemy XII of the Ptolemaic dynasty, it was extended on all four sides to form a small temple,
        12 by 15 metres, which was dedicated to Isis of Philae. The Roman emperors Augustus and
        Tiberius completed its decorations.

        \n\nFrom the quay there is a long processional way leading to the stone-built enclosure wall,
        through three stone pylon gateways and finally to the temple itself. The pronaos, which had
        four columns with composite capitals collapsed in 1868, and is now lost. Behind it lay the
        original sanctuary of Amun, the offering table room and a later sanctuary with several
        side-rooms and stairs to the roof.

        \n\nIn 1960, due to the construction of the Aswan High Dam and the consequent threat posed by
        its reservoir to numerous monuments and archeological sites, UNESCO made an international
        call to save this rich historical legacy. As a sign of gratitude for the help provided by
        Spain in saving the temples of Abu Simbel, the Egyptian state donated the temple of Debod
        to Spain in 1968.

        \n\nThe temple was rebuilt in one of Madrid\'s parks, the Parque del Oeste, near the Royal Palace
        of Madrid, and opened to the public in 1972. The reassembled gateways appear to have been
        placed in a different order than when originally erected. Compared to a photo of the
        original site, the gateway topped by a serpent flanked sun appears not to have been the
        closest gateway to the temple proper. It constitutes one of the few works of ancient
        Egyptian architecture which can be seen outside Egypt and the only one of its kind in Spain.
    </string>

    <string name="palacio_real">
        The Palacio Real de Madrid (literally: Royal Palace of Madrid) is the official residence of
        the Spanish Royal Family at the city of Madrid, but is only used for state ceremonies. King
        Felipe VI and the Royal Family do not reside in the palace, choosing instead the more modest
        Palacio de la Zarzuela on the outskirts of Madrid. The palace is owned by the Spanish State
        and administered by the Patrimonio Nacional, a public agency of the Ministry of the Presidency.
        The palace is located on Calle de Bailén (Bailén Street), in the Western part of downtown Madrid,
        East of the Manzanares River, and is accessible from the Ópera metro station. Several rooms
        in the palace are regularly open to the public except during state functions. An admission
        fee of €12 is required except for residents of the Iberian Peninsula.

        \n\nThe palace is on the site of a 9th-century fortress, called mayrit, constructed as an outpost
        by Muhammad I of Córdoba and inherited after 1036 by the independent Moorish Taifa of Toledo.
        After Madrid fell to Alfonso VI of Castile in 1083, the edifice was only rarely used by the
        kings of Castile. In 1329, King Alfonso XI of Castile convened the cortes of Madrid for the
        first time. Philip II moved his court to Madrid in 1561.

        \n\nThe old Alcázar ("Castle") was built on the location in the 16th century. It burned 24
        December 1734 and King Philip V ordered a new palace built on the same site. Construction
        spanned the years 1738 to 1755[2] and followed a Berniniesque design by Filippo Juvarra and
        Giovanni Battista Sacchetti in cooperation with Ventura Rodríguez, Francesco Sabatini, and
        Martín Sarmiento. Charles III first occupied the new palace in 1764.

        \n\nThe last monarch who lived continuously in the palace was Alfonso XIII, although Manuel Azaña,
        president of the Second Republic, also inhabited it, making him the last head of state to do
        so. During that period the palace was known as "Palacio Nacional". There is still a room next
        to the Real Capilla, which is known by the name "Office of Azaña".

        \n\nThe palace has 135,000 square metres (1,450,000 sq ft) of floorspace and contains 3,418 rooms.
        It is the largest palace in Europe by floor area. The interior of the palace is notable for
        its wealth of art and the use of many types of fine materials in the construction and the
        decoration of its rooms. These include paintings by artists such as Caravaggio, Velázquez
        and Francisco de Goya and frescoes by Corrado Giaquinto, Juan de Flandes, Giovanni Battista
        Tiepolo and Anton Raphael Mengs. Other collections of great historical and artistic importance
        preserved in the building include the Royal Armoury of Madrid, Porcelain, Watches, Furniture,
        Silverware and the world\'s only complete Stradivarius string quintet.
    </string>

    <string name="plaza_mayor">
        The Plaza Mayor was built during Philip III\'s reign (1598–1621) and is a central plaza in
        the city of Madrid, Spain. It is located only a few Spanish blocks away from another famous
        plaza, the Puerta del Sol. The Plaza Mayor is rectangular in shape, measuring 129 m × 94 m,
        and is surrounded by three-story residential buildings having 237 balconies facing the Plaza.
        It has a total of nine entranceways. The Casa de la Panadería (Bakery House), serving municipal
        and cultural functions, dominates the Plaza Mayor.

        \n\nThe origins of the Plaza go back to 1577 when Philip II asked Juan de Herrera, a renowned
        Classical architect, to discuss a plan to remodel the busy and chaotic area of the old Plaza
        del Arrabal. Juan de Herrera was the artist who designed the first project in 1560 to remodel
        the old Plaza del Arrabal but construction did not start until 1617, during Philip III\'s
        reign. The king asked Juan Gómez de Mora to continue with the project, and he finished the
        porticoes in 1619. Nevertheless, the Plaza Mayor as we know it today is the work of the
        architect Juan de Villanueva who was given the glorious, albeit difficult task of its
        reconstruction in 1790 after a series of enormous fires. Giambologna\'s equestrian statue of
        Philip III dates to 1616, but it was not placed in the centre of the square until 1848.

    </string>

    <string name="retiro">
        In 1505, at the time of Isabella I (r. 1474–1504) the Jeronimos monastery was moved from an
        unsuitable location elsewhere to the present site of San Jeronimo el Real Church, and a new
        monastery built in Isabelline Gothic style. The royal family had a retreat built as part of
        the church.

        \n\nKing Philip II (r. 1556–1598) moved the Spanish court to Madrid in 1561. Philip had the Retiro
        enlarged by his architect Juan Bautista de Toledo, and formal avenues of trees were laid out.

        \n\nThe gardens were extended in the 1620s, when Gaspar de Guzmán, Count-Duke of Olivares, Philip
        IV\'s powerful favourite, gave the king several tracts of land in the vicinity for the Court\'s
        recreational use. Olivares determined to build, in a place that the king liked, a royal house
        which should be superior to those villas that Roman nobles had been setting up in the hilly
        outskirts of Rome during the previous century. Although this second royal residence was to
        be built in what were then outlying areas of Madrid, it was actually not far from the existing
        Alcázar or fortress residence, and the location in a cool, wooded area proved to be ideal.

        \n\nIn the 1630s, under the supervision of architects Giovanni Battista Crescenzi and Alonso
        Carbonell, several building were erected in great haste, two of which are still standing:
        the "Casón del Buen Retiro" which served as a ballroom, and the building that housed the
        military museum, the Museo del Ejército, which includes the grand entrance hall, the "Salón
        de Reinos" (Hall of Kingdoms), its wall decorated with paintings by Velázquez and Zurbarán
        and frescoes by Luca Giordano.

        \n\nThe Count-Duke of Olivares commissioned the park in the 1630s, worked on by Cosimo Lotti,
        a garden designer who had worked under Bernardo Buontalenti on the layout of the Boboli
        Gardens for Cosimo I, Grand Duke of Tuscany. Water was a distinguishing trait of the garden
        from the outset: the great pond, Estanque del Retiro, which served as the setting for mock
        naval battles and other aquatic displays, the great canal, the narrow channel, the chamfered
        or bellflower pond, created —along with the chapels— the basic layout of the gardens. Buen
        Retiro was described as "The world art wonder of the time", probably the last great creation
        of the Renaissance in Spain. Buen Retiro became the center of Habsburg court life at a time
        when Spain was the foremost power in the world. During the reigns of Philip IV and Charles
        II several magnificent plays were performed in the park for the royal family and the court.

        \n\nThe gardens were neglected after the death of Philip IV in 1665, but have been restored
        and changed on many occasions, notably after being opened to the public in 1767 and becoming
        the property of the municipality in 1868.

        \n\nPhilip V (1700–1746) ordered the creation of a parterre, the only French-style garden in the
        complex. During the reign of Ferdinand VI, Buen Retiro was the setting for magnificent Italian
        operas. Charles III (1759–1788) saw to the beautification of its perimeter, replacing the old
        walls with elegant wrought-iron railings. Juan de Villanueva\'s Astronomical Observatory was
        built during the reign of Charles IV (1788–1808).

        \n\nThe Buen Retiro Palace was used until the era of Charles III. Most of the palace was destroyed
        during the Peninsular War (1807–1814) with the First French Empire.

        \n\nThe reign of Queen Isabella II saw profound changes in the "Retiro". During the queen\'s minority,
        the gardens enjoyed a particularly prosperous period, with the planting of shade and fruit
        trees, and previously unplanted areas like the "Campo Grande", were landscaped as well. The
        gardens eventually passed to public ownership in 1868, at the time of the overthrow of Queen
        Isabella. In 1883 it hosted the Exposición Nacional de Minería.
    </string>
    <string name="sol">
        The Puerta del Sol originated as one of the gates in the city wall that surrounded Madrid in
        the 15th century. Outside the wall, medieval suburbs began to grow around the Christian Wall
        of the 12th century. The name of the gate came from the rising sun which decorated the entry,
        since the gate was oriented to the east.

        Between the 17th and 19th centuries, the area was an important meeting place: as the goal for
        the couriers coming from abroad and other parts of Spain to the Post Office, it was visited
        by those eager for the latest news. The stairs to the Saint Philip church at the square were
        known as the Gradas de San Felipe, and were among the most prolific mentideros de la Corte
        (this Spanish idiom sounds as "lie-spreaders of the Court", but it is related with the verb
        mentar, "to say about someone", not mentir, "to lie", so it is more appropriately translated
        as "places of the City where people buzz about other people").

        The House of the Post Office was built by French Architect Jacques Marquet between 1766 and
        1768. The building was the headquarters of the Ministry of Interior and State Security during
        the Francisco Franco dictatorship. It is currently the seat of the Presidency of the
        Madrid Community.
    </string>
    <string name="palacio_comunicaciones">
        The current City Hall of Madrid is the Communications Palace ("Palacio de las Comunicaciones"
        in spanish). It is a magnificent building situated along the south side of the Cibeles Square.
        In 2007 the building was transformed into the new home of Madrid\'s city council. Even though
        Madrid\'s city hall looks like a high-gothic cathedral, it was originally built in the early
        20th century as the main office of the Spanish postal service, hence its name Communications
        Palace. It continued to serve that purpose for about a century until November 2007 when it
        took over the function of city hall from the much less impressive "Casa de la Villa" at the
        Plaza de la Villa Square. Its architecture is a combination of the gothic style with neoclassical
        elements. The building\'s facade is elaborately decorated with cartouches and pilasters.
        Long pinnacles adorn the top of the towers, the tallest of which reaches a height of about
        40 meter.</string>
    <string name="teatro">
        Teatro Real (Royal Theatre) or simply El Real, as it is known colloquially, is a major opera
        house located in Madrid, Spain. Opened on 19 November 1850, it closed in 1925 and
        reopened in 1997 with a capacity of 1,746 seats. Today, the Teatro Real opera is one of the
        great theaters of Europe and its seasons are home productions involving leading figures of
        the international singing, musical direction, stage direction and dance. The theater also
        offers guided tours in several languages, including the auditorium, stage, workshops and
        rehearsal rooms.
    </string>
    <string name="teleferico">
        If you want to see Madrid from a bird\'s eye view, take the cable car ("Teleférico de Madrid"),
        Madrid’s most unique tourist attraction, and dates back to 1969.

        \n\nThe journey starts on the Paseo del Pintor Rosales street, near the Argüelles Metro station,
        and takes you over the River Manzanares and into the Casa de Campo park. The cable car carries
        you above the city\'s parks and the Manzanares River in the distance, as a recorded commentary
        describes what you are looking at.

        \n\nYou\'ll be seeing attractions such as the Plaza de España and the Egyptian temple of Debod
        from a completely different perspective, as well as taking photos from several other angles.

        \n\nMany of the city\'s famous sights may be seen, such as the Parque del Oeste Park with La
        Rosaleda (a very beautiful rose garden where annually in May a rose festival is held), the
        Principe Pio Metro Station, the Torrespaña communication tower, the Royal Palace, Almudena
        Cathedral and the Chapel of San Antonio de la Florida (with its grand pictorial decoration
        painted by Francisco de Goya). If you see to the other hand, you will see the part of the
        modern Madrid with the famous 4 Towers buildings.
    </string>



</resources>
